[
    {
       "question": "What does vector have and scalar does not?",
       "options": ["magnitude", "direction"],
       "correct_answer": "direction"
     },
     {
      "question": "Multiply vector by negative number ... its direction",
      "options": ["reverses", "does not change"],
      "correct_answer": "reverses"
    },
    {
      "question": "Initial point of vector is ...",
      "options": ["tail", "head"],
      "correct_answer": "tail"
    },
    {
      "question": "Terminal point of vector is ...",
      "options": ["tail", "head"],
      "correct_answer": "head"
    },
    {
      "question": "When the angle between vectors is 0, vectors are called ...",
      "options": ["parallel", "equal"],
      "correct_answer": "parallel"
    },
    {
      "question": "90 Grad between vectors points out these vectors are ...",
      "options": ["orthogonal", "negative"],
      "correct_answer": "orthogonal"
    },
    {
      "question": "",
      "options": ["", ""],
      "correct_answer": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Addition of 2 vectors ...",
      "options": ["gives a new vector", "changes direction of the first vector"],
      "correct_answer": "gives a new vector"
    },
    {
      "question": "Subtraction of 2 vector is the same as adding ...",
      "options": ["Yes, the same as adding", "Yes, the same as adding a negative vector"],
      "correct_answer": "Yes, the same as adding a negative vector"
    },
    {
      "question": "Vectors addition follows the commutative law",
      "options": ["False", "True"],
      "correct_answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "You can always add or subtract vectors by using a ...",
      "options": ["triangle", "parallelogram"],
      "correct_answer": "parallelogram"
    },
    {
      "question": "Unit Vector is a dimensionless vector with a magnitude of exactly",
      "options": ["0", "1"],
      "correct_answer": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Unit Vector in Data Science can be used in normalization algorithms (feature scaling), gradient descent",
      "options": ["Yes", "No"],
      "correct_answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "Unit vector specifies direction",
      "options": ["Yes", "No"],
      "correct_answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "Symbols 'i', 'k', 'j'  are usually used for unit vectors in 3D space",
      "options": ["yes", "of course not"],
      "correct_answer": "yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "Unit vectors |j|, |i|, |k| form a set of mutually perpendicular vectors in Right-Handed Coordinate System",
      "options": ["yes", "no"],
      "correct_answer": "yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the main difference between Right-Handed Coordinate System and Cartesian Coordinate System?",
      "options": ["Cartesian can be 2D or 3D", "Right-Handed Coordinate System can be 2D or 3D"],
      "correct_answer": "Cartesian can be 2D or 3D"
    },
    {
      "question": "Find magnitude of 3D vector A(3,4,5)",
      "options": ["sq. root of 50", "sq. root of 12"],
      "correct_answer": "sq. root of 50"
    },
    {
      "question": "In linear algebra, a ... ... is a mathematical structure formed by a collection of vectors, along with operations of vector addition and scalar multiplication that satisfy certain properties",
      "options": ["hilbert space", "vector space"],
      "correct_answer": "vector space"
    },
    {
      "question": "Normed Vector Space is ...",
      "options": [" a vector space equipped with a norm, which is a function that assigns a non-negative scalar to each vector, representing its 'length' or 'magnitude'", "a vector space equipped with a norm, which is a function that assigns a negative scalar to each vector, representing its 'length' or 'magnitude'"],
      "correct_answer": "a vector space equipped with a norm, which is a function that assigns a non-negative scalar to each vector, representing its 'length' or 'magnitude'"
    },
    {
      "question": "vectors a = [1, 2] and v=[3,6] are ...",
      "options": ["dependent", "independent"],
      "correct_answer": "dependent"
    },
    {
      "question": "vectors a = [1, 2] and v=[3,4] are ...",
      "options": ["independent", "dependent"],
      "correct_answer": "independent"
    },
    {
      "question": "Span of vectors is a ...",
      "options": ["set of all vectors that can be obtained by scaling and adding them", "the set of all vectors that can be obtained by adding them"],
      "correct_answer": "set of all vectors that can be obtained by scaling and adding them"
    },
    {
      "question": "If the vectors are linearly independent the span is ...",
      "options": ["the entire space they live in If they are linearly dependent", "a subspace of the larger space"],
      "correct_answer": "the entire space they live in If they are linearly dependent"
    },
    {
      "question": "If det(A) == 0, where A are vector1, vector2, etc, than vectors are",
      "options": ["linearly dependent", "linearly independent"],
      "correct_answer": "linearly dependent"
    },
    {
      "question": "Each eigenvector is associated with a corresponding eigenvalue",
      "options": ["yes of course", "can be just eigenvector without eigenvalue"],
      "correct_answer": "yes of course"
    },
    {
      "question": "Eigenvectors exist for any square matrices",
      "options": ["Yes", "No"],
      "correct_answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "Any square matrix has just one eigenvector",
      "options": ["Yes", "No, there can be multiple linearly independent eigenvectors associated with that eigenvalue"],
      "correct_answer": "No, there can be multiple linearly independent eigenvectors associated with that eigenvalue"
    },
    {
      "question": "Eigenvalues and eigenvectors are used in NLP for ... purpose",
      "options": ["context detection", "dimensionality reduction techniques"],
      "correct_answer": "dimensionality reduction techniques"
    },
    {
      "question": "Brackets, Orders (i.e., powers and square roots, etc.), Division, Multiplication, Addition, Subtraction called ... in Math",
      "options": ["precedence", "BODMAS"],
      "correct_answer": "BODMAS"
    },
    {
      "question": "In linear algebra, complex numbers consist of real part and an ...  part",
      "options": ["natural", "imaginary", "fantastic"],
      "correct_answer": "imaginary"
    },
    {
      "question": "x^3+1=0 has no roots",
      "options": ["it has no, because discriminant is less that 0", "it has 3 roots"],
      "correct_answer": "it has 3 roots"
    },
    {
      "question": "In case discriminant of an equation is less than 0, equation has complex conjugate roots, incl. imaginary numbers",
      "options": ["yes, just yes", "no, discriminant is negative, at school I was taught, there are no roots in this case"],
      "correct_answer": "yes, just yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "Is 0 a natural number?",
      "options": ["sometimes - yes, sometimes - no", "definitely no"],
      "correct_answer": "sometimes - yes, sometimes - no"
    },
    {
      "question": "Every natural number is a whole number, but not every whole number is a natural number because whole numbers include zero",
      "options": ["so true", "unbelievable"],
      "correct_answer": "so true"
    } 
       
   
   ]
   